还以为你在为他做圣诞蛋糕
Thought you were making him a Christmas cake.
好吧 谁说圣诞节不能作为爱国的节日
Well, who says Christmas can't be patriotic?
除此之外 他们都已是老手了...嘿
Besides, they were all out of green... hey!
是干净的衬衫吗
Is that a clean shirt?
够干净的了
Clean enough.
这个男人正在飞越6000多英里回家
The man's flying over 6,000 miles to be home
过圣诞节 Tommy
for the holidays, Tommy.
我想我们可以更干净一些
I think we can do better than "clean enough."
呼呼呼
Ho, ho, ho!
-有人在吗 -哦 我的天哪
Hello? Oh, my God.
爸爸
Dad?
我的男子汉
There's my big man.
你早到了
You're early.
-你是在抱怨吗 -不
You complaining? No.
妈妈做了所有你喜欢吃的东西 爸爸
Mom made all your favorites, Dad.
她为你做了烘肉卷和土豆泥
She made you a meatloaf and some mashed potatoes
-还有一个奇怪的圣诞蛋糕... -你妹妹呢 Emma在哪里
and a weird Christmas cake and... And your kid sister. Where's Emma?
哦 那个可爱的小朋友非常想等待她爸爸
Oh, that sweet baby wanted to wait up for her daddy so bad,
但是她从学校回来时有点低烧
but she had to come home from school with a low fever.
哦 可伶的小宝贝
Oh, poor peanut.
我去看看那小孩
Let me see that kid. Aw.
-好 帮我把晚饭抬到桌上 -好的
Okay, help me get supper on the table. Okay.
嘿 宝贝
Hi, honey.
是爸爸
It's Daddy.
该死
Damn.
这个烧是有多低呀 宝贝
How low was that fever, babe?
一小时之前是···37.8度以下
It was... less than 100 about an hour ago.
【美国以华氏度作为温度单位，1摄氏度大约等于33.8华氏度
此处100F大约中国的37.8C】
哦 天哪
Oh, my God.
她要燃烧起来了
She's burning up.
Emma 孩子 嘿 快醒醒
Emma, kid, hey, wake up.
爸爸回来了
Daddy's home.
她几乎不能呼吸了
She's barely breathing.
Emma Emma
Emma? Emma?
快打911 Emma
Call 911. Emma.
求求你了 宝贝 呼吸啊
Please, baby, breathe.
Emma
Emma!
海军
郑重声明：本作品之片源、字幕均来自互联网，仅供个人影视制作的学习、交流之用。版权归发行公司所有。任何组织和个人不得用于任何商业营利用途，否则一切后果由该组织或个人承担。本字幕组不承担任何法律及连带责任！请自觉于下载后24小时内删除。如果喜欢本片，请购买正版！
PS：恭祝飞行猪和加班达人Morning生日快乐 和NCIS一起又老了一岁
罪案
调查处
第十一季  第十一集
翻译：米兰伯爵 飞行猪
翻译：冰糖 秋水冬流
军事顾问： Tom
压制：米兰伯爵
校对：加班达人Morning 小鹿期末要争气
校对：流年圣诞写论文 蓉小张怀念圣诞
字幕特效：老东邪
& GA 字幕组
特别呈献 &
圣诞是一种病
在牙买加的圣诞节 很好呀
Christmas in Jamaica. Nice.
-很好 -不
- Nice? - No, mon.
经历了过去的一年 一点点阳光 沙滩
After the year I've had, a little sun, sand
还有吸一口椰子汁带来的惬意
and sipping cold comfort from a coconut
都会变得很美妙
is gonna be spectacular.
尽管没有什么圣诞节的气氛
Though not terribly Christmassy.
我会带些槲寄生
I'll pack some mistletoe.
【槲寄生常用来作为圣诞节室内悬挂的植物】
你打算怎么过你的圣诞节
How you gonna spend yours?
和我的家人在俄克拉荷马州过
With my family in Oklahoma
我妈妈掌勺
My mom cooking,
我丈夫和我的兄弟们争论足球
my husband and brothers arguing football,
和我爸爸穿着雪鞋远足
snowshoe hikes with my dad.
就这样...
It's gonna be so...
-好有圣诞气氛啊 -是滴
Terribly Christmassy. Yes.
哇
Wow.
看看你 Abby
Look at you, Abby.
-这么喜庆 -这个嘛 毕竟是
So festive. Well, it is, after all, the most
一年中最美好的时候
wonderful time of the year.
-谢谢 -时光
Thank you. Time.
美好的时光 这儿有什么呢
Wonderful time. So what do
-刻字的劳力士 -不
we have here? An engraved Rolex? No.
是我的美好实验室牌自制节日饼干
They're my wonderful lab-baked holiday cookies.
姜饼口味芯片
Ginger spice chip.
你说是实验室自制
Did you say "lab-baked"?
是的 我挥舞着一个快乐的本生灯
Yes. I wield a very merry Bunsen burner.
【本生灯：实验室使用的一种煤气灯 以发明人R.W.本生命名】
恩
Mmm...
为什么McGee脸色那么难看
Why the long face on McGee?
问问是不是水果蛋糕又搞杂了他的命令
Dial-A-Fruitcake mess up his order again?
不知道 有点不对劲
I don't know. Something's wrong.
我进来时他示意我一个手指
He gave me the finger when I came in.
等我一分钟的手指 不是意思不好的那个
The-the "one-minute" finger, not the bad one.
-可能是Delilah -恩
It might be Delilah. Mmm.
感情烦恼 小Tim
Trouble in paradise, Tiny Tim?
【paradise意为伊甸园 此处Tony和Mcgee开玩笑】
呃 不是我们
Well, not for us.
我们的一个朋友 Dalys
A friend of ours, the Dalys.
Kevin昨晚从阿富汗回到家 第一件事就是
Kevin gets home from Afghanistan last night and the first thing
和Audrey匆忙把他们五岁的女儿
he and Audrey have to do is rush their five-year-old daughter
送到急诊室
to the ER.
为什么 发生了什么
Why? What happened?
他们不知道 突然就发生了 只是
They don't know. Out of the blue, it's just...
体温急速上升 气管肿胀到无法呼吸
fever spiked, windpipe swelled shut.
她现在在重症监护病房
She's in the ICU now.
-那太奇怪了 -奇怪
That is so weird. Weird
-和可怕 -恩 不 但是 我的意思是
and horrible. Yeah. No, but, I mean,
我 我的一个海军朋友也在经历着完全一样的事情
I-I have a Marine friend going through the exact same thing.
他儿子本来很健康的
Her perfectly healthy son,
昨天突然倒下了
suddenly struck down and on a respirator.
只能靠呼吸机维持生命
Just yesterday.
-那也太奇怪了 -是啊
That is weird. Yeah.
假期里还有什么比两个病入膏肓的孩子更糟的
What's worse than two sick kids during the holidays?
八个生病的小孩
Eight sick kids.
Carol
Carol.
哇 你在这做什么
Wow, what are you doing here?
我希望它只是一个社交电话 Abby
I wish it was a social call, Abby.
哦...你那样说的时候从来就没有过好事
Oh... It's never good when you say that.
恩恩
Mm-mm.
恩 Bigshop
Um, Bishop,
这是Carol 呃
this is Carol. Um, she works at
她在海军医学研究中心工作
the Naval Medical Research Center now
而且她是我认识最久的朋友
and she's my oldest friend.
我更喜欢长久的朋友（这一说法）
I prefer "long-time" friend.
【oldest也有最老的意思】
老大 你是说
Boss, did you say
有八个生病的小孩
eight sick kids?
都得了同样的神秘疾病
All with the same mystery illness,
而且全都在华盛顿周边30英里范围内
all within 30 miles of DC.
一种传染病的开始吗
Start of an epidemic?
或者更糟--全都来自军人家庭
Or worse-- all are from military families,
住在军属住宅区
living in military housing.
不 不
No. No.
-没有人可以说 -生化袭击
Nobody say it. Bioterror.
除了Abby
Except Abby.
Abby能这么说 但是其他人不行
Abby can say it but nobody else.
额 我 我上个月刚看了一个
Uh, I-I just read a study last month
权衡这种可能性的报告 我的意思是说
that weighed this possibility. I mean, what better way
还有什么比通过孩子来恐吓军事人员更好的方法
to terrorize military personnel than through their kids?
关于这个 没有什么“更好”一说
There's nothing "better" about it.
即使这样 我也足够了解生化袭击 谢谢
I know enough about bioterror as it is, thank you.
这件案子我们只需要知道 它是什么
All we need to know in this case is what it is,
哪里开始的 怎么阻止它
where it started and how to stop it.
你说的是'我们'
You said "we."
这不是我们通常办的案件
It's not our usual case, but it is Navy and
但它涉及到海军和海军陆战队的家庭
Marine Corps families.
他们想让我们加入这次调查
They want us in on the investigation.
直到我和Abby得到科学鉴定结果之前
While I work the scientific end with Abby.
我们与疾病预防控制中心合作
We're coordinating with the CDC.
我的部门正把所有的数据发送到这
My office is sending all our data here.
好的 那我们还在等什么 走吧
Well, what are we waiting for? Let's go.
好的
All right,
分头行动 去医院
split up. Hit the hospitals,
采访家长 和孩子们谈话
interview the parents, talk to the kids,
追溯他们的活动路径 行动
retrace their steps. Let's go.
绝对的 Gibbs 无论需要多少人力
Absolutely, Gibbs, whatever manpower we can spare.
是的 那么 让我们查出是什么让这些孩子...
Yeah, well, let's find out what's making these kids...
让我们竭尽全力
Let's do what we can.
这些孩子怎么了
These kids what?
你说 是什么让这些孩子
You said, "What's making these kids..."
然后又不说了
and then stopped.
爸爸不会再把工作带回家了 Jared
Daddy doesn't bring work home anymore, Jared.
你知道的
You know that.
所以
So?
你可以在车上告诉我
He can tell me in the car.
小家伙 你们最近感觉怎么样
How have you guys been feeling lately?
-什么 类似健康呀 聪明呀
What? Like, health-wise?
恩 恩
Mm-hmm.
我们很好
We're fine.
没有咳嗽 没有头疼
No coughs? No headaches?
没有 目前都很好 为什么
No. All good here. Why?
我们去学校吧
Let's go to school.
那是Jared
Is that Jared
和Kayla吗
and Kayla?
孩子们 去车里等着
Kids, go wait in the car.
那么你就是...
And you would be...
Leon Vance
Leon Vance?
Lamar Addison
Lamar Addison.
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
我想不到的是 你是怎么找到我家的
What I don't know is how you found my home.
你不是唯一一个有资源可用的人 主任
You're not the only one with resources, Director.
这儿没你什么事
You have no business coming here.
哦 但是我的确有事
Oh, but I do.
而且没有必要用挑衅的语气
And there's no need for that confrontational tone.
我肯定不是来找麻烦的
I'm certainly not looking for trouble.
所以我建议你在被发现之前 回到纽约
Then I suggest you go back to New York, before it finds you.
我只想说你好
I only want to say hello.
这样的话 那么 你好
Well, then, hello.
再见
And good-bye.
爸爸 那家伙是什么人
Who was that guy, Dad?
什么人都不是 Jared
Nobody, Jared.
他谁都不是
He's nobody.
最糟的是不能做任何事来帮她
Worst part's not being able to do anything to help her.
所有我们能被告知的就是 Emma是那些有相同病症
All anyone can tell us is that Emma's now one of 14 kids
-的14个孩子中的一个 -14个
going through the same thing. -14?
而且治疗对他们都不起作用
And not one of them is responding to treatment.
医生仍不知道他们面对的是什么
Doctors still have no idea what they're dealing with here.
-McGee -好了 不用担心 Kev 他们会好的
McGee. Well, don't worry, Kev. They will.
恩 只要齐心协力
Uh, just hang tight.
等我一会 马上回来
Give me one second. I'll be right back.
你知道数量上升到14个孩子了吗
Did you know the number's up to 14 kids?
你知道病毒的繁殖率和非典型肺炎一样吗
Did you know that rate of reproduction puts it on par with the SARS virus?
你认为那是非典
You think it's SARS?
我不认为是什么 我的意思是 非典从来没有
I don't think anything-- I mean, SARS has never been contracted
在美国境内传染 有...
inside the U.S. There's...
一个比这更好的 有针对性的化学攻击机会
a better chance of a targeted chemical attack than that.
化学攻击
A chemical attack?
额 抱歉 我...我不是指...
Uh, I'm sorry. I-I didn't mean to...
纯属猜测 Audrey
Pure speculation, Audrey.
是的 也不是没有那种可能
Yeah, and not all that likely.
我只是在统计学方面说
I was just speaking statistically,
-把它比作非典病毒 -哦 天哪
comparing it to the SARS virus. Oh, my God,
-是非典吗 -不
i-it's SARS? - No, no...
-不不不不 我只是...-你是否有可能去其他地方
No, no, no, no. I was only... Could you maybe do your comparing
作比喻 拜托
somewhere else, please?
好吧 抱歉 亲们
Yeah. Sorry, guys.
过来
Come on.
想像下你不得不在这样的旁白下工作
Guess you're gonna have to work on that stage whisper.
就像我感觉还不够糟一样
Like I don't feel bad enough?
Tony 嘿
Tony, hey.
额 非常严重 你呢
Uh, pretty awful. How 'bout you?
不 Bigshop 算了
No, Bishop, let it go.
等等 什么
Wait, what?
19个生病的小孩 我们只听说有14个啊
...19 sick kids. 19? We just heard 14.
过去1小时 这里再出现了5例
...five more cases over here in the last hour.
在Washington又发生了至少5起这样的案例
There's five more cases at Washington General
在最近这段时间里
in the last hour.
Tony有他们的地址么
Does Tony have their locations? I'm putting
我正把他们的位置合在一张图上
together a map. Tony, send Bishop
Tony 把他们的地址发给Bishop
their locations.
-我们必须阻止这一切 -恩 我知道
We gotta stop this. Yeah, I know.
这到底是什么鬼东西
What the hell is this thing?
我能回想起主要感染孩子的
The last infectious disease I recall
最后一场传染病是
that primarily affected children was...
小儿麻痹 当然 那种传染病
poliomyelitis, which, of course,
在这个国家已经消失几十年了
was eradicated in this country decades ago.
你知道么 Mallard医生 虽然它主要传染孩子
You know, while it was mostly children, Dr. Mallard,
但小儿麻痹对成人的折磨却超出人们的想象
polio afflicts more adults than people think.
最近的一次大规模爆发是在纳米比亚
Most recently during a pretty nasty outbreak in Namibia,
2006年
2006.
真的么 在纳米比亚 有意思
Really? Namibia. Interesting.
我上了一些流行病学的课程
I took a few epidemiology classes
自从DiNozzo探员感染鼠疫让大家都吓到了之后
after Agent DiNozzo's Y. pestis scare years ago.
【Y. pestis：Yersini pestis 由耶尔森氏杆菌;鼠疫杆菌】
噢
Ah.
对 我们研究了相当多的
Yeah, we studied quite a few maps
和这个看上去很像的地图
looked just like this one.
有什么相同点么
There anything familiar?
恩 这个分布让人想起了
Well, the pattern is reminiscent of the...
1961年爆发的那场
cholera outbreak of 1961
几乎毁了印度尼西亚的霍乱
which devastated Indonesia.
那个 也可以说成是1885年
That, or the early stages of Montreal's smallpox epidemic
蒙特利尔发生的天花疫情的初级阶段
of 1885.
那起疫情持续了8年多
That one left over 3,000 dd.
Abby呼叫Gibbs 过来  Gibbs
Abby to Gibbs. Come in, Gibbs.
Abby呼叫 噢 嘿 伙计们
Abby to Gi... Oh, hey, guys.
难道我不小心按成了连接Ducky的按键了么
Did I hit my Ducky button by accident?
-嘿 Abbs 你发现了什么 -哦 你在这啊
- Hey, Abbs. What do you got? - Oh, there you are.
你绝对不会相信这些堆积如山的医疗数据
You would not believe the mountains of medical data
都是NMRC送过来的
that the NMRC sent over.
【NMRC:Naval Medical Research Center海军医学研究中心】
Carol和我需要好几天才能彻底理清它
Carol and I could be days combing through it.
-先给我一个初期猜想 -太早了 Gibbs
Give me an early guess. Too early, Gibbs.
我是说 这很显然是呼吸道或者支气管的问题
I mean, it's obviously respiratory, bronchial.
-现在只能祈祷这只是细菌感染而非病毒 -Sciuto女士
Hopefully it's bacterial, not viral. Ms. Sciuto,
还需要一个人来帮助你们
would an extra pair of hands be useful
处理这些数据么
with all this data?
当然了 Ducky
Well, always, Ducky.
你来帮忙么
You offering?
不是我 但是Palmer先生已经是这个领域的专家了
Not me. But Mr. Palmer has become an expert in the field.
我 我还没达到专家的份上 但是 额
I-I don't know about expert, but, uh...
快点下来 Jimmy 让我们打的这些传染病屁股尿流
Come on down, Jimmy. Let's kick some epidemic butt.
你确定么 Mallard医生 你不介意么
You sure, Dr. Mallard? You wouldn't mind?
我为什么要介意自己出的主意
Why would I mind my own idea?
-你呢 -你不用问我的意见 去吧 Palmer
You. Don't look at me, Palmer. Go.
你就指望我们吧 Gibbs
You can count on us, Gibbs.
Abby下线了
Cabby out.
恩
Hmm...
纳米比亚
Namibia.
这么多孩子和军事基地
More kids, more military bases.
很难不让人联想到生化袭击 Gibbs
It's hard to look at this and not think bioterror, Gibbs.
搜索每个角落
Pursuing every angle, yeah.
好的 时刻汇报新情况 海军部长想知道最新消息
Well, keep the updates coming. SECNAV wants in the loop.
恩 好的 明白
Yeah. Yeah. Figured.
你还好么
You all right?
恩 我很好
Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine.
你确定么
You sure?
是担心小孩子么
Kids?
恩 是的
Mmm. Yeah.
我遇到一个不速之客
I had a visitor.
和Jackie不久前进监狱的的兄弟Michael一样
So did Jackie's brother Michael, in prison the other day.
这次是谁
Who?
Lamar Addison
Lamar Addison.
他在纽约有一个人汽车代理连锁店
Owns a chain of car dealerships up in New York.
Michael说他有许多关于Jackie
Michael said he had a lot of questions about Jackie,
和孩子们的问题要问
about the kids.
嗯 那他和Jackie是什么关系
Well, who is he to Jackie?
她的父亲
Her father.
是Jackie和Michael的父亲
Jackie and Michael's both.
当他们还是孩子的时候他就离开家了 而且再也没有回来
He walked out when they were kids and never came back.
和Jackie聊天的时候 我还以为她父亲去世了
Talking to Jackie, I always got the impression he was dead.
-只有我们这样认为 -我可以帮忙做些什么
Only to us. Anything I can do?
这是我的私人问题 Gibbs
It's a personal matter, Gibbs.
好吧 如果有什么要帮忙记得来找我
Okay. Anything I can do?
谢谢你 Gibbs
Thanks... Gibbs,
但我能处理好
but I got this.
喔
Wow.
这些孩子的病非常严重
These kids are really sick.
不会太久的 Jimmy
Well, not for long, Jimmy,
因为我们一定会战胜它
'cause we're gonna lick this thing.
我是说 不是字面上的“舔”它
I mean, not... not literally lick it.
【lick 字面上是舔的意思，这里Abby怕Jimmy误解】
那只是表面的意思
That's just gross.
打扰了 Abby
Excuse me, Abby?
嘿 Breena
Hey. Breena!
Breena 很高兴见到你
Breena, so good to see you!
-恩 这是Carol -你好
Um, this is Carol. Pleasure.
嗨 很抱歉打扰你工作了 Jimmy
Hi. I'm sorry to bother you at work, Jimmy,
-但是Ducky说能在这里找到你  -哦 没关系 一切都好么
but Ducky said you'd be here. Oh, it's fine. Is everything okay?
恩 事实上 非常好
Yeah. Great, actually.
中介已经给我们找到了一位代孕妈妈
The agency may have found us a birth mother.
-什么 真的么 -他们希望能尽快和我们见面
What?! Really?! They want to meet with us soon.
-比如后天 -一个孩子
Like day after tomorrow. A baby!
这...这实在是太棒了
That's-that's great!
这 这...这太不可思议了
It's-it's-it's... it's amazing.
额 我们还是先别庆祝了 怎么样
Um, let's not celebrate, okay?
现在还不是时候 不是时候 我们还有许多工作要做
Not yet. Not yet. We still have so much work
Breena 就先问问
to do here. Um, Breena, just
他们想什么时候见面
find out what time they want to meet,
我们会很开心到那里见面
and, um, we will be there... with bells on.
像过圣诞那样的开心么
Christmas bells?
当然啦 当然啦
You bet, you bet.
过会儿我打电话给你 孩子他爸
I'll call you later... Daddy.
好的 好的
Okay. Okay.
哇哦 好的
Wow. Um... okay.
我真为你们俩开心
I'm so happy for both of you! Yeah.
伙计们
Guys?
我也很为你们开心
I'm really happy, too,
但是如果我们中间 有一个人能查出那是什么
but I'll be a lot happier when one of us can figure out
我会更开心的
what that is.
从来没有见过像这样的东西
Never seen anything like it.
我们真的
We have a lot
有好多工作得去做了
of work ahead of us.
等一下 别走
Wait, back up.
你真的得过鼠疫么
You really had the plague?
像那种真正的瘟疫 得过么
Like, the actual plague, plague?
肺鼠疫
Pneumonic plague.
【肺鼠疫(pneumonic plague)是一种生存于啮齿类与跳蚤的一种
人畜共通传染病 并藉跳蚤传染给各种植物及人类】
我们很熟 互相直呼其名
We were on a first-name basis.
【此为Tony自嘲真的得过鼠疫】
之前我以为你得了妄想症
And here I thought that you were just being paranoid.
想象出一部狗血的电影
One too many cheesy outbreak movies.
哦不 这是真实发生的事情
Oh, no. It's the real deal.
哦 当然 我也可以假设一下
Wow. Of course, I could site,
你明白么 就像《传染病》
you know, <i>Contagion</i>
【Contagion 即《传染病》2011年美国科幻电影】
或者说《惊变28天》那样子的电影
or <i>28 Days Later</i> as major influences.
【28 Days Later即《惊变28天》一部颠覆传统活死人片 而更注重描写人性的恐怖片】
后面那个不是是僵尸快打么
Isn't that last one a zombie flick?
【Zombie Flick Full Fat:僵尸快打 玩家在游戏中利用周围的一切能使用的道具来阻止僵尸前进的一款游戏 】
哦 够了 这有不同么
Oh, come on. Like there's a difference?
区别 DiNozzo
The difference, DiNozzo,
区别就是还没有人被吃掉
is that nobody's been eaten... yet.
我们开始
Let's go.
受感染孩子的人数已经高达23个了 老大
Number is up to 23 afflicted kids, boss.
Bishop 你要和我们一起来么
Bishop, are you joining us?
事实上 我正在努力追上你们的进度
Oh, actually, I'm chasing a lead here.
对了 Abby可真是个做姜饼的天才
Abby's a genius with ginger, by the way.
我妈妈在我一年级毕业的时候
My mom made me a batch like these
也给我做过一些这个
for my first-grade graduation.
和这些差不多好吃
These are right up there.
你还有更多想要分享的么
Your lead good enough to share?
啥 哦 不是 恩 不是
What? Uh, no. Uh, not yet. Um...
马上就好 你想要吃点么
very soon. Do-do you want... Are you sure
-你确定一点也不想吃么 -我不喜欢姜
you don't want any? I don't like ginger.
-好的 -无论如何也别放姜到你的曲奇里
- Okay. - Not in your cookies, anyway.
你是个黄皮肤的男人
You're a cinnamon man.
喜欢那个黄皮肤的女孩
Like the cinnamon girl.
Neil Young 这只是一个比喻
Neil Young, and it's just an analogy.
【Neil Young 加拿大民谣老将 这里Tony引用了其歌曲
“Cinnamon Girl”里的歌词】
一系列对红头发的隐喻 什么
Sort of a redheaded metaphor. What...?
McGee说了什么重要的事情么 他说了什么
McGee was saying something important. What was it?
23个孩子感染了 还有他们都出自军人家庭
23 kids, and other than being from military families,
除此之外没有别的共同点
there's just not much common ground.
经过这条路径的孩子只有九个在这四所学校
Only nine kids crossed paths at these four schools.
我们还跟踪了他们的课外活动
We're still tracking extracurricular activities--
了解了活动的日期以及运动的队伍
play dates, sports teams.
发现了什么
What?
没 什么都没发现
What? Uh... oh, nothing.
只是快发现了
getting closer.
已经足够了 快说
Close enough. Spit it out.
噢 先等我确认一些联系
Uh, not until I verify a connection.
说 Bishop
Spit, Bishop.
好的
Okay.
我正在查看政府监视名单
Well, I was checking the government watch list,
无意中发现了一个最近才加进去的人 叫Max Comey
and came across a recent addition named Max Comey.
在那上面发现他最近被Burke的一个化学研究设施
On it. Recently fired from Labsynthe,
Labsynthe开除
a chemical research facility in Burke.
曾被指控获取他本应该处理的
He was accused of taking a variety of toxic mold spores
多种有毒霉菌孢子
he was supposed to dispose of.
-他要用那些有毒孢子做什么 -这上面没有提到
Taking it to do what? It doesn't say.
我是想说 虽然没有完全构成犯罪
I mean, while not exactly a crime,
也有足够理由来解雇他了
it was grounds enough for a dismissal
而且他的动向也显示在政府监视清单上
and his placement on the government watch list.
明白了 我去找他
All right, I got him.
当前住址是在Pax River的Harwood Place
Current address is on Harwood Place in Pax River.
【Pax River: Patuxent River Naval Air Station, Maryland 帕图克申特河海军航空站（马里兰州）】
稍等一下 Harwood Place
Wait a second. Harwood Place.
和这些学校的其中一所在同一个街道上
It's the same street as one of these schools.
这是巧合么
Coincidence?
我可不这么认为
I don't think so.
Comey上周也因为
Comey was also red-flagged last week
与一名海军陆战队的征兵人员打架而被警告
for fighting with a Marine Corps recruiter
那刚好是在他的求职申请被拒绝之后
after he was refused an application.
对 因为他在政府监视清单上
Yeah, because he was on the watch list.
这就是动机  McGee 从这里下手
It's motive. McGee, keep working it from here.
DiNozzo Bishop 过来 你们跟我走
DiNozzo, Bishop, come on, let's go. You're with me.
哦
Oh.
他的前门开着
Leaves his front door open.
你想起了谁么
Remind you of anyone?
NCIS
NCIS!
壁橱是空的 抽屉也是
Closet's empty. Drawers, too.
搬出去的很匆忙啊
Moved out in a hurry.
如果是我的话
Where would I keep toxic mold spores
会把有毒霉菌孢子放在房间的什么地方
at my house?
恩
Hmm?
噢 一些可能有毒的剩饭
Ew. Some pretty toxic leftovers.
我找到了些东西
I got something here.
那么 无论Comey从实验室偷走的是什么
So, whatever Comey stole from the lab, he either
他要么用掉了 要么带走了
used or took with him?
喂 Duck
Yeah, Duck.
恐怕我们的神秘疾病有了它的第一个受害人
I'm afraid our mystery illness has claimed its first fatality.
-是那些孩子中的一个么 -不是
- It's not one of the kids. - No.
但也许只是时间问题
But it may just be a matter of time.
当一起传染病发生时
When it comes to infectious diseases,
老人和小孩一样脆弱
the old are just as vulnerable as the young.
我担心事情往往会在它们变好之前
I'm afraid things may be getting worse
变得更差
before they get better.
受害者是Lloyd Grunfeld 71岁
Victim is Lloyd Grunfeld, 71,
不久前丧偶 是一名越战老兵
recently widowed, Vietnam vet.
在过去的31年里
The last 31 years,
他在Quantico经营一家干洗店
he's managed an on-base dry cleaning shop at Quantico.
地区医院说他昨晚登记住院时
District Hospital says he checked in last night
和那23个孩子有着相同的症状
with the same symptoms as our 23 afflicted children.
28个
Twenty-eight.
高烧 呼吸困难
Uh, sky-high fever, respiratory distress, but
但在医院给他分配床位之前
before they could get him to a bed,
他就倒下了 死在了急诊室的地板上
he collapsed and died on the ER floor.
好的 我们已经把他家隔离
All right, we've got his home quarantined
直到查出他的死因
until we know what killed him.
-Comey的协查通告有消息吗 -还没有
What about the BOLO on Comey? No hits yet.
房东说他租金还没到期
The landlord said he was close to eviction, but
但却自己搬出去了
moved out on his own.
我们和实验室
We spoke to some
他以前的同事谈过
of his former co-workers at the research lab.
听起来Max医生是个相当古怪的家伙
Sounds like Dr. Max was a pretty odd guy.
-医生？ -医生 医生
- Doctor? - Doctor, Doctor.
他就是这么称呼自己
That's what he called himself.
他把这份实验室助理的工作看的太认真了
Took his job as a lab assistant a little too seriously.
切 也就他自己觉得重要
Boastful, self-important.
尤其是有女士在身边时
Especially around the ladies,
她们觉得他比女人还烦
who considered him more annoying than dangerous.
【dangerous 意指女人】
直到他带走了霉菌孢子
That is, until the mold spores went bye-bye.
这些东西含多少毒份
How toxic are these things?
毒性下限 没有像炭疽病那样要命
ll, not exactly anthrax,
【ll low limit的简称 意为下限】
但如果长时间摄取或者吸入
but they could certainly make a person sick
也足够让人生病
if ingested or inhaled over time.
这需要接触（才能传染）
It's got to be connected.
好的 我们已经
Well, we've requisitioned surveillance
申请监视Grunfeld地区和那些孩子
on Grunfeld and some of the kids.
看看他们是否通过路径
See if they crossed paths.
喂 Duck
Yeah, Duck.
-Jethro 你能下来吗 -好的 马上就来
Jethro, can you come down? Yeah. Be right down.
这是什么
That's it?
没有“好样的”
No "Nice job,"
或者“好主意 伙计们”
or "Good idea, guys"?
没有
No?
这夹克不错
It's a nice jacket.
好的
Okay.
讨厌承认这一点 Mallard医生
Hate to admit it, Dr. Mallard,
但是当你叫我来帮你时我真的非常欣慰
but I was pretty relieved when you called me in to assist.
所有感染病例都在Abby的实验室
All those infection cases in Abby's lab.
这些可怜的孩子
Those poor kids.
压力山大啊
It's pretty overwhelming.
比起孩子和正在忍受病痛的人
Elderly and deceased is a far easier concept to confront
老人和死者更容易面对
than young and suffering.
现在 领养孩子已经成为可能
And now, with this adoption becoming a real possibility,
我不禁在想自己是否已经准备好了
it's got me wondering if I'm even ready.
准备什么
Ready?
成为一位父亲
To be a father.
过着操心的生活
Consigned to a lifetime of worry.
会有各种各样的麻烦
There are so many things that can go wrong.
呃 也许会这样
Well, that may be true,
但回报是远超过风险的
but with the rewards far outweighing the risks,
我确定你可以胜任
I'm sure you're up to the task.
我很高兴你给了我肯定
I'm glad one of us is sure.
Gibbs探员
Agent Gibbs.
嘿 Duck
Hey, Duck!
有好消息吗
What's the word?
退役的Grunfeld中尉身上的惨剧
Retired First Lieutenant Grunfeld's misfortune
可能会成为孩子们的救星
may well be the savior to many children.
死因是什么
What's the cause of death?
一种极具攻击性的肺炎病菌的变种
An extremely aggressive strain of pneumonia.
是的 他的气管和肺部都感染了
Yeah, his trachea and lungs were besieged by it.
能治愈吗
Treatable?
对一个年事已高的糖尿病患者来说 不能
Not to a man of his advanced years and diabetic condition.
但是 对原本健康的孩子来说
But, uh, previously healthy children,
可以 应该能完全治愈
yes, it should be quite treatable.
真的吗 医生
Really, Doctor?
那太...太好了
That's...that's wonderful!
嘿 Palmer
Hey, Palmer?
事情总是往好的方向发展
Things do go right sometimes.
哦 你...你听到刚才的对话了
Oh, you...you heard that earlier?
是的
Yeah.
就是说 如果Abby和Carol
That is, provided that Abby and Carol
能够从那些培养物里
can identify the specific strain of pneumonia
鉴定出肺炎病菌的具体变异
from those cultures.
我马上把这些拿给Abby和Carol
I will get these up to them right away.
好的
Yeah. Good.
请进
Come in.
我谢谢你的邀请
I appreciate the invitation,
但不过你没有必要派你的喽啰来
but you didn't have to send your henchmen.
那些喽啰可是联邦探员
Those henchmen are federal agents.
孩子的保姆发现有人潜入我家
Sent after a phone call from my children's nanny
给我打电话之后我才派去的
concerned about a man stalking my home.
敲门完全算不上是潜入啊 Leon
A knock on a door is hardly stalking, Leon.
顺便说下 我的赞美
My compliments, by the way.
那位保姆...她是个非常有魅力的女性
That nanny...she's a very charming woman.
这一点很重要
And that's important.
对向前看很有益处
It's good to move on.
向前看 你刚刚是说"向前看"吗
Move on? Did you just say "move on"?
你是指 像你过去抛妻弃子一样吗 Addison
You mean, like you moved on from your wife and kids, Addison?
- 你说的是这个意思吗  - Millie和我没有结过婚
- Is that what you mean?  - Millie and I were never married.
所以这一切就都是对的吗
So it's all good then?
你对自己一无所知的事情就妄下结论吗
You making judgments about things you know nothing about?
你知道自己留下的烂摊子吗 Addison
Do you realize the mess that you left behind, Addison?
Jackie和我被迫留下来收拾
The mess that Jackie and I were left to clean up
你关心过儿子的去向吗
where your son is concerned?
除了发现Michael进了监狱这件事
Considering I found Michael in prison,
你收拾地还是不错的
you did a real fine job.
以前我一直以为
And here all this time, I thought
Jackie夸大了对你的描述
Jackie was exaggerating when it came to you.
不 那就是我
No. That was me.
我很抱歉
Regretfully.
不知怎么的 旧事重提让我想起了
Somehow digging all this up has me reverting back
一些老的坏习惯
to some old, bad habits.
你确实有不少坏习惯
And you had quite a few of 'em.
有过 是"有过" Leon
Had. <i>Had,</i> Leon.
我有过一些坏习惯
I had a few.
但人是会改变的
But people change.
而现在我唯一的希望就是
And my only hope now is
能补偿过去 并用行动告诉我的孙子们
to make up for lost time and show my grandkids
我不是他们听说的那种坏人
I'm not the villain they may have heard about.
没有必要
There's no need.
Jackie是那么善良 从不说你一句坏话
Jackie was too good to speak ill of you.
事实上 她从来没有提过你
Never spoke of you at all, in fact.
只要我的孩子们问起来
As far as my children are concerned,
我们就说外公已经去世很久了
their mother's father is long dead.
出于对Jackie的尊重 我希望能维持现状
Out of respect to Jackie, I intend to keep it that way.
我想我唯一能问的是 还有什么办法能让你改变主意吗
I suppose all I can ask is, any way I can change your mind?
我愿意支付他们的大学学费
I could pay for their college tuition
如果你能重新考虑的话
if you would reconsider.
我的孩子不是用来交易的
My children are not for sale.
Kurtwell探员 你能有好地护送Addison先生
Agent Kurtwell, would you kindly escort Mr. Addison
到他的车上吗
to his car, please?
Leon...我不是那个意思
Leon...that's not what I meant.
老人家 如果你再去敲我家的门
You darken my door again, old man,
我的探员就不是把你带到这里了
my agents will not be bringing you here,
我保证
I can promise you that.
- Gibbs  - 有好消息吗 Abbs
- Gibbs!  - Got news for me, Abbs?
是的 表面上看Grunfeld老先生是死于
Yup. Looks like old man Grunfeld died of
肺炎链球菌
<i>Streptococcus</i> <i>pneumoniae.</i>
跟以前的链锁状球菌不同
Didn't look like strep before,
但是培养物呈现阳性反应 而且和
but the cultures came back positive. And it's the same bacterium
- 孩子们感染上的病菌是同一种  - 那么 现在怎样了
- that's been infecting the kids?  So, what now?
刚给医院打了电话
Just called the hospitals,
那时他们正在使用正确的抗生素
and they're administering the correct antibiotics as we speak.
治愈应该只是时间问题
Should just be a matter of time,
孩子们会非常健康的
and the kids will be right as rain.
为健康的孩子们和成为父亲的Jimmy干杯
Here's to healthy kids, and Jimmy being a daddy!
喔 喔 但是
Whoa, whoa, but,
我还只是有可能成为父亲 Abby
uh, that's still just potentially, Abby.
不想高兴地太早
Don't want to get ahead of ourselves.
这次 我支持Palmer
For once, I'm with Palmer.
等等 你支持我吗
Wait. You are?
看上去Grunfeld几乎没有离开过他的商店
Looks like Grunfeld hardly ever left his store.
他确实处理了一大堆脏衣服
He did handle an awful lot of dirty clothes.
跟孩子相比 毫无共同点
Nothing compared to this kid.
18号患者 Josh Baker
Patient number 18, Josh Baker.
孩子就是一个行走的细菌培养皿
Kid's a walking Petri dish.
Emma Daly也是
Same with little Emma Daly here.
这些孩子很少生病
It's nothing short of a miracle
绝对算得上奇迹
these kids don't get sick more often.
- 好了 我们现在查看的是什么  - Grunfeld和一些患病孩子的
- Okay, what are we looking at?  - Surveillance and home videos
监控录像和家庭视频
of Grunfeld and some of the kids.
查看他们生活中的交集
Looking to see where they may have crossed paths,
或者找出他们接触过的任何东西
or picked up whatever they picked up.
他们似乎接触过各种东西
They seem to pick up everything.
这是肺炎链球菌
It's strep pneumonia.
- 等等 什么  - 他们接触到的东西
- Wait. What?  - What they picked up.
Abby认为是肺炎链球菌
Abby thinks it's strep pneumonia.
医院已经在治疗这些孩子
The hospitals are already treating the kids.
肺炎链球菌
Streeumonia?
仅此而已
That's it?
好像可以治愈
It, as in cured?
老天 太棒了
Oh, my God, that's great!
不 这还不够
No, it's good.
等我们找到0号患者
Great'll be when we find Patient Zero
切断源头的时候 那才好呢
and shut down the source.
说得对
Right.
吝啬鬼先生
Okay, Mr. Scrooge.
不是说你小气或贪便宜之类的
Not that you're stingy or cheap in any way.
我只是...因为...圣诞节到了
I was just... because of the... Christmas.
这样可以
This is
减压 干得好 各位
a relief. Good job, everybody.
你还好吗 McGee
Are you okay, McGee?
我很好
Yeah, yeah.
我只是想起小Emma
I was just thinking about little Emma here,
和Daly夫妇...他们肯定很高兴
and the Dalys...they must be so happy.
是啊 他们和我都很高兴
Yeah. Them and me both.
用那样的方式吓唬他们 我感觉很糟
I felt terrible about scaring them the way I did.
你还没忘掉这事儿
You still haven't gotten over that?
貌似他们不会
Well, like they didn't have enough
那么难过 如果我没有猜测说
on their plates without me suggesting
这是一起有针对性的化学袭击的话
a targeted chemical attack.
我干过更过分的事情 McGee也
I've done worse, and McGee...
他...记得跟...一起的时候吗
Well, he's... Remember the time with the...?
我还是不说了
I'm not gonna talk about it,
不过这事...这事已经过去了
but it's... it's been done.
即使你犯了错误 你还是要向前看
You just have to move on. You made a mistake.
一个严重的错误
A big mistake.
吸取教训 继续前进
Learn from it, move on.
我最终会的 Gibbs
I will, Gibbs, eventually.
要很快...Bishop
Soon... Bishop.
这是为了你好
For your own good.
Leroy Ebenezer Gibbs,
咱俩刚才是不是达成共识了
did we just agree on something?
嘿 Bob Cratchit 找到0号患者了吗
Hey, Bob Cratchit, find Patient Zero, huh?
还有一个有趣的电影参考资料
And a playful movie reference.
真的开始像圣诞节了
It really is starting to feel like Christmas.
更像圣诞节的早上
More like Christmas morning.
刚从协查通告那得到消息 Max Comey已经找到了
Just got a hit on the BOLO. Max Comey's been located.
- 我们出发  - 等等
- Let's go.  - Hang on.
你们说过这个家伙喜欢女人 是吧
You said this guy likes the ladies, right?
什么
What?
嘿
Hey.
你能跟我介绍一下那棵树吗
Could you tell me about this tree over here?
额 可以肯定的是它和其他的树一样绿
Um, pretty sure it's green like the rest of 'em.
- 是啊  - 是啊
- Yeah.  - Yeah.
就是...就是这里的这棵
It's, uh... it's this one right over here.
嗯
Hmm.
你以前不是在Labsynthe工作吗
Didn't you used to work at Labsynthe?
我...我上个月在那儿临时工作过一段时间
I...I temped there last month.
你是Max医生 对吗
You're Dr. Max, right?
- 是的  - 是啊
- Yeah.  - Yeah.
没错
That's right.
你是...
Yeah, you were...
你是其中一个聪明人
you were one of the smart ones.
怎么...怎么你在这工作呢
What are you... what are you doing working here?
说来话长
Long story.
- 他们开除了我  - 什么
- They, uh, let me go.  - What?
- 真的吗  - 他们让我住在我的货车里
- Seriously?  - They've got me living out of my van.
像我这么聪明的人 沦落到卖圣诞树
A guy like me, reduced to selling trees.
你能相信吗
Can you believe that?
不 我不相信 那...
No, I can't. That is...
那太不公平了
That's so unfair.
我知道 很不公平 对吧
I know, right?
不过 他们很快就会知道他们犯下了错误
But, uh, they'll know they've made a mistake soon enough.
我会展示给他们的
I'll show them.
他们
Them?
他们指的是谁
So, who's "them""
Max
Max?
具体展示给他们什么
Show them what exactly?
我们从货车开始吧 好吗
Let's start with the van, huh?
我没有什么可藏的
I got nothing to hide.
看我们找到了什么
What do we have here?
没有什么可藏的吗
Nothing to hide, huh?
那不是我的
That's not mine.
我...我...我从来没有见过这个
I...I...I've never seen that before in my life.
真的
Really.
那...那...
That...that...
我没有偷任何东西
I didn't steal anything.
是实验室先扔掉了它
The lab was throwing that stuff away.
绝对是携带病毒的霉菌孢子
Perfectly good toxic mold spores.
你为什么带着这些
Why take them?
或许我喜欢自己做实验呢
Maybe I like to do my own experiments.
一个普通人没有必要成为 比如 一个真正的医生
A guy doesn't have to be, like, an actual doctor
去拯救世界
in order to save the world.
那是你的计划吗
Is that your plan?
去拯救世界
To save the world?
但是在那之前 你首先
But in order to do that, you'd have
要让整个世界都生病 是吗
to make the whole world sick, right?
不是整个世界 不是的
Not the whole world, no.
那么是谁 Max
Then who, Max?
是拒绝你的海军陆战队吗
The Marines after they rejected you?
或者是孩子们
Maybe the kids.
不是孩子 一直都不是
Not kids. Never.
你们能保证不告诉她吗
Do you promise not to tell her?
我们保证
We promise.
是Bernadette
Bernadette.
我的女朋友
My girlfriend.
我们怎样才能找到她呢
How do we find her?
她是Megamart的出纳员
Well, she's the cashier over at the Megamart.
你想让她生病
You want to make her sick?
我知道这很愚蠢 但是
It's stupid, I know, but
我算计着 如果我能够帮她康复
I figured if I helped her feel better again,
她可能会更欣赏我
she might appreciate me more.
那一点也不愚蠢
That's not stupid at all.
事实就是 我仍然在研究总体治疗的部分
Thing is, I'm still working on the whole cure part.
我不想在没有治疗办法之前让她生病
I didn't want to get her sick without that.
毕竟 我不是个禽兽
I'm not a monster, after all.
我不敢苟同
<i>I beg to differ.</i>
这个人有妄想症
<i>This man is delusional</i>
和潜在的危险
and potentially dangerous.
最好找到这个Bernadette
Better go find this Bernadette.
如果她确实存在 我怀疑
If she exists, I doubt
她知不知道Max的所为
that she's aware that he does.
他们的关系 我肯定
Their relationship, I'm sure,
完全是他虚构的
is entirely in his mind.
而他所持有的霉菌孢子
And the mold spores he possesses,
可能会让人病得很严重
while they might make someone quite sick,
我并不确定它们能否变成肺炎链球菌
I'm not convinced they'd turn into strep pneumonia.
这不是肺炎链球菌
It's not strep pneumonia.
那到底是什么
What is it?
所有的医生一致同意
Well, all the doctors agreed
我们最初的发现
with our initial findings,
但是孩子们对肺炎链球菌的抗生素毫无反应
but the kids aren't responding to the antibiotics for strep.
看上去像是细菌产生了变异
And it seems like the bacterium is mutating
变成了其它的细菌...一些
into something else...something
更 更 更糟糕的 我真的 真的是没用
way, way, worse, and I'm really, really bummed.
我们俩也是
That makes two of us.
所以我们又回到一无所知了
So we're back to not knowing?
好的 你拘留Comey直到我们找到办法吧
Right. You'll keep this Comey fellow in custody till we do?
我来开门
I'll get it.
好的 Gibbs 有消息随时告诉我
All right, Gibbs. Keep me posted.
你以为我在开玩笑吗
Did you think I was kidding?
你真的以为我在虚张声势吗
Are you really calling my bluff?
求你了 Leon
Please, Leon.
在离开之前我有件事必须说出来
I have just one thing I want to get off my chest before I go.
求你了
Please.
就两分钟
Two minutes.
回想过去 我离开Jackie的母亲是有原因的
Looking back, I had my reasons for leaving Jackie's mother...
在当时 对我来说很重要的原因
reasons that made sense to me at the time.
你觉得她配不上你
You thought she was beneath you.
Jackie是这么想的吗
Is that what Jackie thought?
不 这不是Millie的问题 是我的问题
No, it wasn't Millie's shortcomings, it was mine.
那时很傻很天真无法面对他们 所以我离家出走
Being too young and foolish to face up to them, I took off.
和另一个女人组建了新的家庭
New family, new woman.
打算彻底抛弃过去
A do-over.
人无法尽善尽美
Most folks don't get one.
我已经尽力去做了
I made the best of mine.
我生意做的不错
I built a good business,
培养了三个优秀的孩子
and raised three great kids.
然后就忘了被抛弃的那两个
Forgetting about the two that you left behind.
他们让我不断回忆起以前的失败 Leon
They reminded me too much of my failures, Leon.
只有在Jackie写信给我后
Only realized after Jackie wrote me, that
我才意识到  对于那些所谓的成就
here I was, this big success, who
我从未感受过真正的成功
never truly felt successful.
什么意思 她写过信给你
What do you mean, she wrote to you?
去年圣诞节时写的
Last Christmas.
我没有回信
I didn't write back.
我做不到
Couldn't.
一个月后 我在电视上看到她被杀的消息
And then, a month later, I saw on TV that she was killed.
为什么我女儿会在这么多年后
Why would that little girl write this old man
给我写信
after so much time?
因为她真心爱你
Heart.
Jackie全心全意的爱着你
Jackie was all heart.
你知道的 几年前
You know, um, some years ago when I heard
当我听说她嫁给了你 拥有体面的社会地位
that she was marrying a man of your position,
一想到这我就很宽心
I felt so relieved to think that,
如果不出意外的话 她会过得很安逸
well, if nothing else, she would be safe.
不要误会
Don't get me wrong.
我没有怪你
I don't blame you.
同理来说 你也不能因为
But at the same time, you can't blame me
我想念她的孩子 担心孩子的安全
for wondering about her kids
而责怪我
and about their safety.
你明白我的意思吗
You hear what I'm saying?
十分清楚
Loud and clear.
但你不必担心什么  Addison
But you don't have to worry about anything, Addison.
只有一件事不用担心
Don't have to worry about a thing.
现在不行 以后更不可能
Not now, not ever.
你就像以前那样 只需关心你自己就好
You just take care of you, like always.
顺便说一句 Jackie没有写信给你
And Jackie didn't write to you,
我们实话实说吧
by the way-- let's get that straight.
Jackie会在这些卡片上
Jackie would write notes on those cards
给她关心的老朋友写祝福语
to old friends,
但其中并没有你
to people that she cared about, but not to you.
就连我们的清洁工收到的祝福卡片
Hell, even our trash collector
都比你的多
got a more personal card than you got.
但还是到我的手里了
It still came.
她还是邮寄出去了
She reached out.
也许她就只是想让你知道
Maybe because she wanted you to see
没有你她也一样活得精彩
what she accomplished without you, in spite of you.
你才会后悔 这是你罪有应得
You got regrets, that's on you.
但这并不代表我和我的孩子们就会尽释前嫌的原谅你
But it's not up to me and my kids to make 'em go away.
你说的很对
Ain't that the truth.
我道歉 Leon
I apologize, Leon.
你们好好过个愉快的节日吧
You have yourself a happy holiday.
还是没有结果
I don't get it.
现在 病毒已经对孩子们的皮肤造成损伤
Now the bacterium is causing lesions on the kids' skin.
很明显 Grunfeld在被找到之前就死了
Obviously, Grunfeld died before they could form on him.
Ducky也只找到了早期治疗方法
'Cause Ducky only found the early stages.
大学毕业后就没有这么通宵达旦的工作了 Abby
Haven't pulled an all-nighter since college, Abby.
还能坚持住吗
You up for it?
我们别无选择
It's not like we have a choice.
但你可以 先回家吧
But you do. Go home.
你和孩子的妈明天要和医生会面
You have a meeting with your birth mother tomorrow.
没有了 我取消了
No, not anymore. I'm canceling.
什么 不要啊
What?! No!
我们必须争分夺秒的进行研究
We've been rushing things anyway.
不 你不需要
No, you haven't.
别再想我孩子的事了  Abby
Forget about my kid, Abby.
好吗  这些孩子怎么办
All right, what about these kids?
我不走
I'm not leaving.
直到我们找到根源
Not till we figure this out.
好吧...
Okay...
可以...
All right...
好的...
Okay...
34个了
34.
谢谢
Thanks.
老大 已经有34个被感染的孩子了
Boss, number's up to 34 sick kids
安排在从朴茨茅斯到巴尔的摩的八个医院
at eight different hospitals from Portsmouth to Baltimore.
而且病情持续恶化
And they're all getting worse.
这些家庭不得不
These families had to have come in contact
互相间保持联系
with each other at some point.
我们在这里追踪每个家庭
We followed up with everyone here.
有一些家庭互相认识 但不是亲近的朋友
Uh, some acquaintances but no close friends.
绝大多数学生在不同的学校上学
Most of the kids attend different schools.
几乎没有交集
There's barely any crossover.
DiNozzo那里有消息吗
Any word from DiNozzo?
他还在华盛顿医院
He's still at Washington General.
我再和他核对下
Let me check in with him.
我过去一下很快回来
I'll be right back.
不好意思 上尉
Excuse me, uh, Lieutenant?
Mrs. Daly
Mrs. Daly?
我为昨天的事道歉
I wanted to apologize for yesterday.
我 我不是故意把事情搞得糟糕
I... I didn't mean to make matters worse.
你没有
You didn't.
Tim告诉我们你为此自责不已 请你...
Tim told us how badly you felt, and... please, we...
我们知道每个人都在竭尽全力
we know everyone is just doing the best that they can.
那这样的话
Well, in that case,
介意我跟你说一些事情吗
uh, do you mind if I tell you something?
是关于天花的
It's about smallpox.
你确定我们想听吗
Are you sure we want to hear this? And, uh,
麻疹和小儿麻痹
measles and polio,
白喉 牛瘟 钩虫病 风疹
diphtheria, rinderpest, hookworm,
还有可能是一些别的什么 我忘了
rubella and probably a few others I'm forgetting.
可能会是这些疾病吗
What about them?
这些疾病
These are all diseases
都曾被认为是无法治愈的医学难题
that no one knew how to cure at one time.
但是现在它们都消失了
But now they're gone...
被铲除了 所以今天的未知病毒也会消失
eradicated, just like this thing's gonna be.
上帝会保佑Emma的
Statistics are on Emma's side.
谢谢你
Thank you.
感觉好些吗
Feel better?
是的
Yeah.
这些人要去哪
Where's everybody going?
他们给非医护员工放假了
I believe they're sending nonmedical personnel home.
Abby的朋友
Friends of Abby's?
准确的说是圣诞老人的助手
I think the technical term is Santa's Helpers.
糖果舞姬之类的
Candy stripers.
我们昨天在这见过这些志愿者
Volunteers. We saw them here yesterday.
哦 我知道该怎么做了
Oh, I know that look.
你熬夜工作了
Have you been working all night?
是的 主任 早上好
Yes, Director. Morning.
早 先生
Morning, sir.
我发现海军少尉Dorothy Williams
I've got Navy Ensign Dorothy Williams.
四天前在安纳波利斯的聚会上当过志愿者
Volunteered at the Annapolis party four days ago.
Williams在安纳波利斯 核实一下
Williams at Annapolis. Check.
嗨 你到的很早
Hey. You're in early.
是的 睡不着 这些都是什么
Yeah. Couldn't sleep. What's all this?
寻找病原体
Looking for patient zero.
我们在交叉对比
We're cross-checking volunteers
出现在海军基地聚会的志愿者们
at all military base holiday parties.
有27个受感染的孩子
Turns out 27 of our afflicted kids
上周都参与过至少一场以上的聚会
attended at least one of them in the last week.
我发现Mike Russo下士
I got Petty Officer Mike Russo.
三天前在海军大院的聚会当过志愿者
Volunteered at the Navy Yard party three days ago.
海军大院的Russo 正在核实
Russo at the Navy Yard. Check.
他们都是军职人员吗 -不全是
Are they all military personnel? -Don't have to be. Could be anyone.
餐饮公司 圣诞老人的助手 充气球的人谁都有可能
Caterers, Santa's Helpers, guy blowing up the balloons.
病毒诊断上有进展吗
Any progress on the diagnosis?
正要问Abby -好吧 ，没事
About to check with Abby. No, that's okay.
我去看看 你继续调查
I'll go. You keep at it.
你已经够忙的了 Gibbs
Can't say you're not thorough, Gibbs.
嗨  Leon
Hey, Leon.
你听过万福玛利亚的祈祷词吗
You ever heard of a Hail Mary?
早
Morning.
大家查的怎样了
How's everybody holding up?
我办公室刚送来这个
My office just sent these.
病人皮肤病变部位呈紫色斑点状
The lesions have started turning purple, which narrows down
这有助于帮我们缩小查询范围 但远远不够
the search a bit but not enough.
具体原因我们还没有查出来
Not yet anyways 'cause we're not done.
谢天谢地我还没有孩子
I am so not having kids.
好吧 Jimmy 不要抱怨了
Okay, Jimmy, that does it.
不好意思 主任
Excuse us, Director,
Palmer似乎被什么附体了
but something has gotten into Mr. Palmer,
我希望让那东西赶快消失
and I would like to get it out now.
好吧 可别让我插手
Well, don't let me interfere.
Abby 听着...不 你才该听好
Abby, listen... No, you listen.
你知道节日该有的涵义是什么吗
You know what's infectious
是乐观
during the holidays? Optimism.
乐观可以感染一切
Optimism is infectious.
乐观
Optimism and...
还有愉悦 还 还有善良
joy... uh, joy and-and... Kindness.
对 善良
kindness.
礼节 还有慈善
Courtesy. And charity.
慷慨
Generosity.
感恩
And gratitude.
无私
Selflessness.
怜悯
Compassion.
宽容
Forgiveness.
宽容的概念很大
Oh, forgiveness is huge.
善良
Kindness.
你已经说过善良了
You already said kindness.
我喜欢善良这个词
I like kindness.
还有信念
And faith,
Jimmy 信念
Jimmy. Faith.
信念也是应该有的涵义
Faith is infectious.
生活不会一帆风顺
Life isn't always perfect,
你明白吗 如果你有信念的话
you know? But sometimes things
那么事情就会有转机
work out for the best if you just have faith.
好吧 Abby
Okay, Abby.
好的
Okay.
好 我们查到哪了
Okay. Where were we?
我们查到...-呃，你们查到...
We were... Well, you were...
你们查到的地方
As you were.
我拿一些热咖啡下来
I'll have some fresh coffee sent down.
还有不加咖啡因的 可以吗
And some no-bean caffeine, please?
Abby
Abby.
Gibbs 你没法悄悄接近我了
Gibbs, don't sneak up on me like that.
病毒有没有可能
Is there any chance that this bacteria
来自于非洲
came from Africa?
非洲
Africa?
如果是是特定于只在非洲传播过的话
If it's specific to Africa,
就能解释为什么
that would help explain why we're having
我们花了这么大力气还是找不到病因
so much trouble finding it.
为什么 Gibbs 谁来自非洲
Why, Gibbs? Who's from Africa?
可能是病原体
Possible patient zero.
没准就是圣诞老人
Otherwise known as Santa Claus.
圣诞老人 圣诞老人 圣诞老人
Santa Claus? - Santa Claus? Santa Claus?
也就是
Also otherwise known
海军上尉Louis Boggs
as Marine Captain Louis Boggs.
这个人在海军基地扮演了好几年的圣诞老人了
Guy's played Santa Claus at military base parties for years.
最近刚刚结束在刚果的特殊任务回国
Recently returned from a special operation in the Congo.
刚果 在最近几周内 他是唯一一个
The Congo? And he's the only person
出现在每场海军聚会上的人
who's been to every military holiday party
这就意味着他可能传染了
in the last few weeks. Which means he's come in contact
每一场聚会上的孩子们
with nearly every kid at every party.
我们不明白的是他是怎么传染Grunfeld的
What we don't know is how he came in contact with Grunfeld.
不，我们知道原因
Yes, we do.
我记得我从哪见过Grunfeld在柜台边
I knew I'd seen a red suit
检查一套红衣服
go over Grunfeld's counter.
这是一周前的监控
This is from a week ago.
这不就是Boggs 是的
Isn't that Boggs? Yeah.
好的 找到他 进行隔离
All right, find him. Get him quarantined
直到有人确定他到底携带了什么病毒
till somebody figures out what he's got.
你说的“有人”就是指我们吧 Gibbs
That somebody is about to be us, Gibbs.
Abbs 刚才关于刚果的信息有帮助吗
Abbs, the Congo gets us closer?
已经确定了 Gibbs
Congo gets us there, Gibbs.
我查到了
I got it.
是A群脑膜炎
Meningococcal A.
A指的就是非洲 明白吗 这种病从未发生在美国
"A" as in Africa. See? You'd never find that here.
这就是我们之前一直很难确认病因的原因
Which is why we couldn't find it before.
能治疗吗
Can it be treated?
用相应的抗生素就可以治愈
Yeah, with the right antibiotic, sure.
打电话给医院
Call the hospitals.
通知每一个人
Call everybody!
大家做的好
Great job, everybody.
嗨 爸爸
Hi, Daddy.
亲爱的宝贝
Hi, honey.
...特别激动
...so excited about it.
是的 我 我很激动
I am. I am. I am. I am.
Jared Kayla
Jared, Kayla,
他是我之前跟你们说道过的
this is the man that I told you about.
Addison先生
Mr. Addison.
你们母亲的父亲
Your mother's father.
你们的外祖父
Your grandfather.
谢谢你
Thank you.
漫长的冬天需要冬眠
<i>Time for a long winter's nap.</i>
我要去赶夜航航班啦
I'll grab mine on the red-eye.
正好
Oh, that's right.
俄克拉荷马州的时间
Oklahoma time.
正好是家人团聚的时刻
Family time.
阿门
Amen to that.
我丈夫在机场等我
My husband's meeting me at the airport.
需要搭车吗 不 我只要...
You need a ride? Oh, no, I'll just...
我打车就好  别傻了
I was gonna grab a cab. Nonsense.
我和McGee
Me and Mr. McGee are just heading out
正打算出去喝几杯
for a little cocktail.
顺便送你吧
We'll drop you off on the way.
我没同意要跟你去喝酒
I never agreed to a cocktail.
我也没问你啊
I never asked.
来点蛋酒么 ‘以便以谢’
Eggnog, Ebenezer?
【注：“以便以谢”，出自《圣经》，意为“助人之石”，希伯来人战役得胜
立石碑感谢神，名为“以便以谢” 此处为Tony对boss戏称】
不用了 你去吧 明天见
No. Go on. See you tomorrow.
那好吧
Bah, humbug.
晚安 老大
Night, boss.
你不明白什么是“睡不醒的冬三月”
What part of "long winter's nap" do you not understand?
一点麦氏托迪酒不会喝多的
One little McToddy won't hurt you.
我 我差点忘了
I, uh... I almost forgot.
Tony说你喜欢肉桂
Since Tony said you like cinnamon,
我想...
I thought...
你应该尝尝我妈妈做的咖啡蛋糕
you might want to try my mom's coffee cake.
每次吃这种蛋糕都让我有种幸福感
It always makes me so happy and, well,
我们都应该得到幸福 Gibbs
we all deserve to be happy, Gibbs.
尤其是在即将到来的节日
Especially this time of year.
无论如何...
Anyway...
圣诞快乐
merry Christmas.
也祝你圣诞快乐 Bishop
Merry Christmas to you, Bishop.
==GA字幕组==
翻译:米兰伯爵 飞行猪 冰糖 秋水冬流
校对：加班达人Morning 小鹿期末要争气 流年圣诞写论文 蓉小张怀念圣诞
字幕特效/时间轴/：老东邪
压制 : 米兰伯爵    军事顾问： Tom
冰糖：圣诞那天下雪吧^^
伯爵：今年的圣诞一路向北~
佳晨：求不再加班，让我好好过节专心复习吧
流年：圣诞假期，我和boss一样坚守在岗位上学习。。
小李：这集字幕有点多 因此我翘了一节课
蓉蓉：冬歇冬歇~
猪猪：圣诞快乐~